Call me with a momma. The Reggers get her made a momma city council for Tuesday, February 20th, 2024.
Publicians put on schedule personal appearances. We have none. Three claims list.
Motion. Second.
Hi. Is that a Williams?
Hi.
Perfect.
Five. Four minutes from February 5th, 2024, Regger meeting.
Motion.
Second.
Is that a Williams?
Hi.
Perfect.
Five. Budget amendment number 24-08.
Receiving an expending $304 additional funds in state aid for the Oklahoma Department of Libraries.
C24-07 for the library. Receiving an expending insurance recovery and building scrap metal revenues.
Fire.
Receiving an expending $14,756 to purchase the four sets of bunker gear that were lost during the public works fire.
On April 23.
The streets expending 15,234 dollars and 25 cents to replace the equipment that was lost in the 988 dollars and 98 cents for building cost to date.
Remaining building replacement costs will be managed by the facilities.
309,845 dollars and 68 cents.
So this amendment does several different things.
One. The library got in more money from state aid than we had budgeted for them to get.
So that $304 extra dollars they want to be able to spend it.
So it's doing that.
And then on the fire that occurred April of 23.
We have expenditures.
We've replaced equipment.
We replaced bunker gear and we've done a little bit of work on the building.
So we've spent some money.
We spent some money last year and we spent some money this year.
And what this does, it makes everything even.
And it moves whatever's left out of our insurance recovery as of today.
It moves it to facilities so they can now use that money for the replacing building.
And remember that this time last year or April we were talking about a possible transfer out the rainy day fund for the remainder of the cost of the building.
That will still happen.
We just don't know where we're at.
Do we receive this money that for 15,000?
Yes.
And we actually expect to receive some more money.
But we just want to catch everything up for now.
Where do they expect to cost of getting this completely finished?
Like, yeah, that number can.
Not yet.
We've had the contractors.
I do have to put it back in the same spot. It's not favorable. I thought it would be because that
creature runs through there and stuff like that. So we're going back to ground zero, starting
to the ground up. Yeah, by the days for locations. Do be somewhere on that side. We're looking
back on that side. Oh, I got you. So it will still be in the same area and I just want to make a motion.
Can we prove it? I'm sorry. Williams. Hi. Hi. Hi. Six master service agreement with the
Anderson engineering owners for the engineering services. This is just a motion to prove.
Second. Hi.
Williams. Hi. Parker. No see way to get all well.
Episode seven member of agreement with the upcoming Department of Wildlife Conservation for the
Pile Fish Boom Bill fishing program and ratify city mangers signature. Was that $1,000 go to
as it go to South Africa. South Africa in the orgrace to the go ramps.
That's part of the spring. That's a free berman. You're just to apply a permit. It was
a permit that would be charged to a fee for him.
But we entered into agreement with wildlife several years back
that rather than as charging for that permit,
they were paying us a bigger sum of money.
But since the youth got it, the caviar market,
they're not doing near as much stuff now.
We had collected our fees as past season.
We would have gotten a lot less money than like this $1,000.
And they're taking that into consideration.
We lost your seniors, a research center.
We lost the research center now.
Historically, there were a lot more pathophysch
that were checked in years past.
And so that agreement with the state was around five.
$5,000 a year in lieu of us asking people to get city-printed criminalized.
The problem is that the harvest has dramatically dropped off, where there used to be hundreds
back in, and say 2010, there may have been 700 petal fish checked in, last year there were
19, and a year for that to be like 60, so it's dramatically reduced. So to them, there's nothing
driving them to help us drive down costs of a permit, and there's no sense in us
permitting something we're not going to make you money on where you're going to run away
in the language we have. This is probably the best deal we can get for now, and we'll see
what's with the future of the petal fish. The reason they want to appreciate that they would like to see
that part of the petal fish, they're still wanting the water to come back to a patient part.
And they do want to be very helpful. I mean, they're not wrong, and there's a lot of
the fingers we could be helping throughout the year, rather than just a small period during
the spawn of the petal fish. So there's great opportunity here, and they are wanting to be
good partners who's a stock of trap, Mr. Lowman, and it's a problem with you.
Right, I think they're going to go. Motion approved.
Thank you.
So what's up? Hi.
It's step-by-pointing. Hi.
Hi. Thanks, if a moment of part in a various ways, and there are not its grant application
and Federal Aviation Administration grant applications for the new airport terminal.
I'll throw a city manager to execute the grant documents and subsequent related paperwork.
So this is the actual grant document that goes to ODA, the change of route passes.
We'll re-tap just a little bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit of a
total project is right at 3.2 million. Right now, the city's part is 1.2 million.
Two nine council groups are approved. 1.2.
We are working with the contractor to get that down, out of the contact with them.
This is just the grand document to send in ODA. ODA has already approved the project.
Depending on the arrival of our airport, this just sent the paperwork in the four lines of grant.
I'll make motion to approve.
Nine amendments to the outside organizational contracts for fiscal year 2324 for my senior center and
Being a crisis center
In your packet to contracts amended for each of these organizations the senior center. We put them together the senior center when they put in their application last year
The inadvertently put 15,000 when they should have put 18 because that's what it was raised to in the middle of the year last year
So we're correcting that to 18,000 from 15 and then from the crisis center
They came and presented several meetings ago and you want to staff to use a research on that and
In your packet is the BA that shows you their usage over the past few years
The next agenda item
So credits utility credits aren't
expense the same way
What it does is actually reduces emissurate revenue. So
The customer service manager, she builds them and she goes right in and credits their bill
So it's really just a reduction of revenue however you
Indicated you wanted to
Pay using the budget money as you have for the council individually and that so that was a fit. It's gonna be like a 15,000-dollar
expenditure and
the offset to that would be
A budget amendment to decrease the two million go to a general fund by 15,000. So that's the next
Motion we approve
Hi
10 budget amendment 24 to zero nine reducing the transfer from MSUA to the general fund to care of the additional utility credit
$15,000 provide the community crisis in a motion to a proof
Say it
Thank you. 11
Other new business of any
We use a post of reasons that's opposing this agenda
12 staff reports 13 mayor council community now folks
So so I was I was just wanting to
There was a woman in my neighborhood. It was
We got broken into last month. I think just recently and so she she
She goes there alone by so she's 80
I won't mention who she is but she called 911 and stayed up and got them on the phone
They got the police over there within
What she thought was second and and and
They I think there was three officers
total that
It was on the scene they had
Two of them that was tracking this guy that laughed in the snow
And one of one of the officers
Justin Barry
Notersers cameras at my house, so he came over to my house at
Two in the morning and
And and wanted to look at my cameras. So I just wanted to commend
City my officers for the job that they do and I think that just reflects on chief Anderson's leadership
that
What a great job the police department does in general and
The 911 operator that was on there stayed on the phone with her until they got there
And she was just ecstatic about the whole deal. So she thought it was a great job
Made her feel great and so it all went really well
She's got it. She's getting the security system installed at this point. So but but it all went well
But I just wanted to note that
I got another story kind like that. Our girls in our business office
so
Four years ago
I got a lot of calls about the business office
Now I hardly get any and the ones that do get are always positive
The girls in the office are going to great job the care of our citizens
They're really doing a good job
The lady had lost her mother
She was trying to take care of her mother's
Everything final the bills and you know that stuff and our girl if counter was really passionate
Her mother real really good about the situation walk her through how to do it and how to handle it
So the lady reached out to me and and wanted to thank us for for our girls in the office
So they're doing a great job and
I appreciate them very much
Because I'm a call today in conference call and
This conference call all
Several not all but several or travel partners are on that call
And guys
We're extremely fortunate here to have the partner. We do in our travel partners
Some of the stuff we deal with on a day-to-day basis we couldn't do without them
So I know sometimes people feel like that's a a problem for some reason to have travel partners
Got something down yet. It's a huge huge benefit for us. I don't know the town spill about it
But I know for me it's been a huge asset those chiefs are old
these real cognizant of helping us with anything we need.
So that call today made me really realize
those on the call with me as well.
The sooner or more, the better help them fight with things we need to get done.
So I appreciate our travel partners.
I wanted to do this for those of you that don't know, there was an election last.
Well, early in February.
And so Councilman Williams and Councilman Sunberg did not refile and did not rerun.
So the last meeting in April will be their last meeting.
But we do have a lot of our new councilwoman here.
This college owns.
She'll be taking over for Councilman Sunberg.
So if you haven't got a chance to meet her, please say hi to her.
We leave.
I think it's all I've got, so we want to 14 to manage our communications.
I got one thing that I wanted to make note of,
Cali asked me to remind everybody that at the public library, this is financial literacy week.
They have an entire program, guys, of training that's available to the public.
All week long, these are classes that are set up.
They're each about an hour long.
They're scheduled, just like if you went to a conference, but they've got things like investing basics,
loan basics, insurance, auto loans, retirement calculators, mortgages, budgeting, all of these things,
which are available to the public.
It's a great opportunity.
Folks to get out there, I would encourage anybody that's got young adults, that need additional training
after high school.
I know my kids would benefit from this, but it's a great deal they've got set up today.
They had several, but I did go through them and many of those were repeated throughout the week.
So we haven't missed anything if you want to get out there and take advantage of that, but again,
financial literacy week at the public library and they just do an amazing job there.
You can find this schedule online, go to the city website, go to the public library, and they've got the whole schedule available.
Before we adjourn, I want to thank the Boy Scout and further leadership.
Thank you, really well.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you all.
15 adjourn.
Motion.
Second.